DEVIN READEL

318-218-4642

<u>dreadel@bellsouth.net</u> www.linkedin.com/in/devinreadel

Spring Hill, TN

Profile

An Offshore Automation Professional with experience in the GoM and International in Angola. Experience in Commissioning Complete Facilities to small projects. Capable of working in small to large multicultural teams. Can cover Automation, Instrument, or Electrical roles as needed. Skilled in troubleshooting/fixing various production issues with keyboard, wrench, screwdriver, pry bar or hammer.

Experience

ICSS Specialist - BP Angola Africa, Greater Plutonio FPSO - 2010-2015

Lead for the ICSS offshore team and Telecoms offshore team.

Responsible for Automation Server management, Software updates (Production and Business), PLC (Rockwell, HIMA, Modicon, Siemens), DCS (DeltaV) & OPC (Matrikon) maintenance and updating. Also production instrumentation (FieldBus, Profibus, Hart, Wireless) and project commissioning and start-ups. Working closely with Sunbury(UK) and Luanda(Angola) Engineering on project ideas, MoCs, and equipment installs.

Automation Specialist - BP America, GoM Marlin - 2006-2010

Responsible for Automation Server management, Software updates (Production and Business), PLC maintenance and updating, production instrumentation, and project commissioning and start-ups. Also working closely with Houston Engineering on project ideas, MoCs, and equipment installs.

I & E Technician - BP America, GoM Marlin VK-915 — 2004-2006

Instrumentation, Electrical & Controls support for BP

Automation/Systems Tech - Kellogg Brown and Root, Lafayette LA - 2001-2004

Instrumentation, Electrical & Controls support for BP, Conoco, and Vastar as a production team member.

More experience/details in my LinkedIn Profile

Education

Copiah Lincoln Community College - Natchez, MS — 1995-1997

Associates in Instrumentation and Electronics

Nashville Software School - Nashville, TN — 2015

A full time six month bootcamp for software engineering and web development covering full-stack development.

References

Available upon request.